In this clip, we're going to talk about, you know, the proper set up procedures when you're inflating your kite and how to really designate whether or not this is the right place to do it and you know, just the general procedures about it.
Each kite, all these companies use different, specific systems where, you know, you're going to be inflating the kite.
Right here, these are the dump valve, so obviously, before you start pumping up your kite, you're going to want to put that up.
And something you're definitely need for this whole procedure here is a pump.
It's definitely a funny thing when you come out to the beach and you see some guy sitting there and he's about to pass out because he's been trying to blow up his kite with his mouth.
So, first things first, you know, make sure you have your gear and make sure you've taken a lesson so you know how to do this.
But, you know, get your pump and you're going to want to set your kite up perfectly in orientation to the wind.
So, right now, it feels a little bit windier.
I could probably just hold this out and the kite would just unravel on its own and everything would just be immediately swept downwind.
So, that's the best way to set the kite up.
One thing to look for before you start pumping is make sure your bridles, these things right here, aren't wrapped around the wingtips of the kite.
Sometimes, if you inflate the kite all the way and, you know, for instance, this is just totally wrapped up into it, you just made this into a rigid structure and it's got a line that's completely just sort of twisted around it and just one little gust in the wrong direction and it can just serrate it right apart.
So, what we're going to do is, we're going to attach our pump leash to the connection point that's provided on the kite.
Different companies, like I said, use different systems.
This is a slingshot rev and, as you can see right here on the dump valve, there's a perfect place where you can attach the pump leash right there.
So, first thing we do right there, attach that.
And you know, sometimes, if it's really windy, even go the extra step, like put the bridle around your leg or just get somebody to hold the kite while you pump it up.
You want to make sure because this is a one-pump kite, all these struts right here, that's what these are called, these sorts of rib shaped things that are going to provide structure for your kite.
You want to make sure those are unclipped and ready to accept air.
If they're clipped, you're going to pump up your whole kite and then, all of a sudden, you're going to unclip that and, you know, you're going to have to repump your kite up.
So, to make sure this all goes down in one smooth, swift motion, open up all your valves, make sure your dump valve is closed, sealed and definitely put this extra Velcro strap on it because you don't want that popping off out there.
And then, you can go ahead, insert your nozzle and you can see there's a little ball right down in there, so this is technically a one-way nozzle.
But sometimes, you've got to be a little extra fast and quick when you're plugging this out.
You just take it, put your finger over, and then cut it off, Velcro down, and then now we have this really cool little slingshot patented clip that we can actually stick right here to make sure our valve is going to stay down.
I've personally done a five mile swim in from the water because I didn't have one of these things and the rubber and the Velcro wore off.
I'm out there and my kite deflated.
That's a basic kitemare right there.
So make sure when you put your kite together you do it all properly, efficiently and, you know, you don't miss any steps.
Once you're fully pumped up, hit this clip right here to isolate the air in all the struts.
That way, in the event that you do get into a kitemare out there, you know, you get a slash in your leading edge, even just a slow leak, something starts to lose air, you're going to isolate air into all these compartments, so you're immediately going to have a flotation aid that's going to allow you get back onto shore safely.
So.